Sarah Al-saeedi

Mobile developer

Address: Heintzestrasse 3, 24143,

Email: sarahalsaeedi16@gmail.com Website: www.sarahalsaeedi.com

Date of Birth: June 12th, 1989

Nationality: Yemen Marital status: married Phone: +49 157 78411075 LinkedIn: sarah-alsaeedi



Professional Profile

Mobile developer specializing in React Native with a solid +6 years of experience. Over the years, I have been able to deliver more than 5 apps to corporate and individual businesses by integrating APIs with third-party services, allowing me to scale applications with advanced features and functionality. From concept to deployment, I take a hands-on approach throughout the app development lifecycle. Looking forward to being a valued member of your team and contributing to the continued success of your company.

Work History

06/2017 - present

Mobile developer

NexStep, Inc - CA/Silicon Valley, USA

NexStep is an IT Services and IT Consulting company focused on IoT support services.

- Developed a React Native app for IoT support services using a variety of APIs, including sockets.io, reset APIs, IBM Watson R&R and QA Services, Amazon IOT, AWS amplify and Alexa.
- Utilized AsyncStorage and other technologies to enhance data storage and retrieval within the application.
- Implemented WebRTC for seamless video and audio streaming.
- Introduced ChatGPT for natural language interactions and integrated text-to-voice/voice-to-text functionalities.
- Implemented a QR code reader feature for quick information retrieval
- · Redesigned and modernized the user interface for improved user engagement.

01/2017 - 09/2019

Mobile Developer

OrderIn Holding LTD – UK

- Developed 3 clean, modular, and robust React Native Realtime apps for a restaurant search provider: a customer-facing app, a restaurant management app, and a delivery driver app.
- Implemented features via RESTful APIs and WebSockets for realtime updates.

06/2017 - 01/2019

Freelance

Self Employed-Freelance Mobile Developer

- Worked as a front-end developer on a team that developed locationbased second-hand marketplace app.
- Developed a mobile app for a sports magazine using in-app navigation, interactive maps, as well as image and file viewers for multimedia content.

01/2014 - 03/2016

Operations Associate

Elitetecs – Startup Technical Solutions-Yemen

 Provided technical support to the company's employees and systems, managed the front desk, and researched and recommended new technologies to the company.

04/2012 - 01/2014

Software Developer

UNIMARK for trademarks and intellectual property – Yemen

 Developed and implemented a trademark system using ASP.NET, as well as maintained computers and worked with Excel sheets.

Other Projects:

2018

Participated in Eclipse Open IoT Challenge 4.0 with open source project Alya-Smart-Mirror, integrating Alexa, voice/gesture recognition, MQTT, Node-Red, React Native.

Education:

2019 – present

Master degree in Computer Science (Informatik) Christian Albrechts Universität (CAU) Kiel – Germany.

2007 - 2011

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Networks University of Science and Technology Sanaa – Yemen.

Online Courses:

Meta React Native Specialization (8 course series)

The Complete React Native + Hooks

Udemy.com

Meta staff - coursera.com

IT-Skills:

Languages:

React native, CSS, Javascript, Git, Node.js, Typescript, Docker, MongoDB, AWS

Arabic (Mother Tongue), English (C1), German (A1)